

## CONTACT

**PHONE:** 

+57 305 306 2521

M EMAIL:

josh.glen.92@gmail.com

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshbrito-79b975182/

ADDRESS:

Cra 41 # 61-32, Barranquilla (Open to relocated)

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C#, Java, JavaScript, PHP, Python (in the process of learning).

Database Languages: PL/SQL, MS SQL server, HSQLDB.

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, React, Bootstrap, wavemaker, SmartFlex Framework

Nivel de Ingles: Proficient C1 (Australia)

## SKILLS

Web application development **Backend Development** Troubleshooting & Debugging SCRUM, XP, CI/CD Problem-solving Attention to detail Empathy

Collective property

Initiatives to hang out with the team

# JOSH BRITO SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### SUMMARY

I am an experienced software developer with more than 5 years of developing web applications. My expertise lies in designing and developing custom solutions aimed at the success of business processes in multiple industries, implementing CI/CD and using agile methodologies (SCRUM, XP). I am currently seeking a role to apply my experience and analytical problem-solving skills. I have a keen interest in Full Stack(BE heavy) development, support or system integration positions. Currently, I am expanding my knowledge in React and Python, technologies I am learning to incorporate into future projects.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer | C# | PL-SQL | React | Javascript | Docker Compose | Java | PHP Olsoftware

Software Developer Engineer • Mar 2020 - Currently freelance worker

- Designing web applications, interfaces with .NET C#, SmartFlex Framework.
- Collaborating with customers to understand their requirements and providing tailored software solutions.
- Integrating data from diverse backend services and databases.
- Conducting research and extracting data from PL-SQL (Oracle) databases using anonymous Block, DML, DDL, TLC, DQL, DCL.
- Analyzing existing SQL queries for performance enhancements.

### **Horbath Technologies**

Web Application Developer Engineer • Nov 2016 - Jun 2021

Supporting and developing to public utility companies (Natural gas companies; Electricity companies; Water companies) Specialized in customer service, accounting, invoicing, construction, and legalisation modules, resolving issues within a collaborative team. Engaged directly with users and negotiated project scopes. Excelled in backend development, SQL queries, and API creation, enhancing technical proficiency in PL/SQL, SQL Commands.

#### **Key Achievements:**

- Research required and extract data with PL-SQL from (Oracle) database engine, interacting with SQL commands.
- Provide general support to development team debugged, diagnosed and corrected bugs and faults by troubleshooting.
- •Generate and maintain program code to meet system requirements (SmartFlex Framework) using programming languages such as C# and PL-SQL.
- Resolved a year-long invoice printing issue, showcasing problem-solving prowess.
- Negotiated project scopes and costs with clients for successful project outcomes.

#### Ticom S.A.

Web and Software Developer • May 2016 - Oct 2016

- Conducted thorough analysis of process needs and requirements.
- Creation of user interfaces / ERP development using the WaveMaker platform, JavaScript, HSQLDB (HyperSal) and Java.
- Develop and optimize PL/SQL code for data manipulation, validation and reports
- Developed accounting, banking, performance statistics, and other modules.
- Emphasized detailed user discussions for comprehensive understanding.

#### Olinsa S.A. Port society

Web Programmer J r • Jul 2015 - Mar 2016

- Analysis of the needs and / or requirements of the processes
- Developed web application / user interfaces / Bootstrap framework / PHP, MS SQL Server, Css.
- Documented quality tests, supported urgent solutions, and developed modules for container inspections, service quotes, work orders, container operations, and fruit quality evaluation for export.

#### EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Engineering - University of La Guajira, 2009 -2014 (Colombia) Adv. Diploma of Information Technology – Academies Australasia College, 2020 – 202 (Australia)